NICHOLAS HERRICK

Aurora, CO 80013

Phone: 720-299-9354 | Email: nick@nicholasherrick.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicholasherrick-dev/ | Github: https://github.com/nicholasherrick | Portfolio: https://nicholasherrick.com/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer & Web Developer with experience in the Denver area. Certified in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Denver. Skills include building and managing full stack applications using mostly Javascript frameworks and technologies and some PHP. Knowledgeable in UI/UX design principles & able to create responsive web pages. Aware of the importance of writing clear, easy to understand code in an organized and uniform process. Recognized as a conscientious and open minded individual that values teamwork, respect, and integrity. Excited to utilize and improve upon my skills while working with a great dev team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages & Markup: Javascript, ES6 & ES7, PHP, JSX, HTML, CSS, SCSS Frameworks & Libraries: React, Redux, Saga, GraphQL, Strapi, Bootstrap, SASS, Express, JWT, Mongoose, Sequelize, Laravel, Jest, Enzyme, Sass, Jquery, Handlebars Technologies: Node, Mongodb, MySQL, AWS Cloud9, Twilio, Git, Heroku, Netlify Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, OOP, Functional Programming

PROJECTS

Mural Map | Mural Map Github | https://muralmap.art/

- Mural Map is a full stack MERN application that allows users to find and discover murals. Using an interactive map with markers, the user can find murals that other users discovered and added to the database
- Solo project, I bootstrapped using next.js and created the backend api & front
 end interactive google map. The most challenging aspect of this project was
 implementing image uploads utilizing multer and cloudinary on the back end.
- React, Next, Node, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Json Web Tokens, Passport, Heroku, Javascript, Multer, Cloudinary, Google Maps API/Geocoding

StaySafe | StaySafe Github | https://stay-safe-fork.herokuapp.com/

- StaySafe is a full stack MERN stack application that allows users to share their location with friends when in potentially dangerous situations. It provides multiple ways to call for help with the press of a button. The app is recommended for use on a mobile device. The most challenging aspect of this project was managing asynchronous code and CRUD calls to the backend API
- Group project, I created the wireframe, documentation and helped with front-end components, styling, and debugging
- React, Node, MongoDB, Mongoose Express, Passport, Twilio, Sendgrid, Bootstrap, Javascript/ES6, Jest, Enzyme, Google Maps Geocoding

Warbler | Warbler Github | https://warbler-client-nh.herokuapp.com/

Warbler is a full stack MERN application that is meant to be similar to twitter.
 Users are able to create accounts, and send "messages" to a timeline for all users to see. Users can delete messages and more features are in the works.

- Solo project, I created the entire back end api and front end react application
 using asynchronous promise handling. The application makes use of global state
 on the front end with Redux and Thunk for promise handling The app also makes
 use of rehydration. It also features consistent and uniform error handling
 throughout the application.
- React, Redux, Thunk, Node, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Json Web Tokens, Bootstrap, Heroku, Javascript/ES2015-2017, Moment, bcrypt

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Web Developer Bluejestic

December 2020 – Current Orlando. FL (remote)

Create Front-End components using React, Next, Redux, Sass, GraphQL, etc. Attend weekly update meetings with the rest of the dev team. Coordinate implementations with other developers across the project.

Teaching Assistant 2U/Trilogy Education Services

December 2020 - Current New York, NY (remote)

Assist students on their journey to become programmers during their 6 month Full Stack Bootcamp program.

Technical Consultant | Full Stack Developer (Freelance) Starlight Foundry

April 2020 – Current Denver, CO

Consult clients on technical needs, design & build applications from scratch based on client's needs, launch, host, maintain & update client applications.

Key Accomplishments:

 Help clients understand the scale & scope of their applications in order to adjust their needs accordingly. Improve performance and efficiency of existing sites.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Denver, Denver, CO

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

CRCST Certificate: IAHCSMM

The Certified Registered Central Service Technician certification program is designed to recognize entry level and existing technicians who have demonstrated the experience, knowledge and skills necessary to provide competent services as a central service technician.

BLS Certificate: American Heart Association

Basic Life Support, The American Heart Association's BLS course trains participants to promptly recognize several life-threatening emergencies, give high-quality chest compressions, deliver appropriate ventilations and provide early use of an AED.

High School Diploma: Denver School of Science and Technology

Some College: Colorado State University, Metropolitan State University